Comes, to lie down
잘 누워
그래야 순산할 수 있어
Lies down, treats can compare quite
When the time comes I call you the mouth to open
You open
힘을 주라고 하면 줘
The mouth holds, like this quite is quick
힘을 줘야 빨리 나와
좋아, 아주 잘 참는군
Is like this very good, very can endure patiently
Also has come, also pain
통증이 또 오는군, 아플 거야
Comes, the mouth holds
힘을 꽉 줘
A little the picture wants the bowel movement, has?
대변이 나올 것 같지? 그렇지?
Has?
Like wants the bowel movement, you make an effort to crowd
Has not related
대변 볼 때와 같이 힘을 줘
괜찮아, 괜찮아
Quickly saw, you have prepared the water
물 좀 빨리 끓여
알았어요
Hands and feet a bit faster
Does your mother, the electricity to present only then
빌어먹을, 이제야 들어오네
Has lived, male... ...
Congratulates, congratulates
사내 아이야
1945년 8월 15일 일본천황은
무조건 항복을 발표했고 대만은
51년동안의 통치에서 해방됐다
임문웅은 팔두자와의 사이에
아들 임광명을 낳았다
비 정 성 시
어서 오세요
Embarrassed, today house at sixes and sevens
Not time... ...
벌써 가시려고요?
Evening must give us to invite
안녕히 가세요
Must go back
Must again come
누가 오셨어요
Welcome
This delivers you, small gift
누구? 뭘 이런걸..
작은 성의입니다
Plays to side... ...
저 쪽에 가서 놀아
여기서 떠들지마
The child also quarrels in there
Again quarrels paternal grandfather must take ? the stick to hit
조용히 안하면 맞는다
여보세요? 나야
I, am
Thanks, thanks
그럼 내가 미안하잖아
Does not use this, embarrassed
번거로우니 그러지마
Does not need that to trouble
Thanks
오후에 꼭 와야 돼
Afternoon certainly must come
기다릴께 알았어
I wait for you, thanks
첫째야, 넷째는 언제 온다고 했냐?
Eldest child
You inform the old four any times comes back
바빠서 지금은 못온대요
Has writes a letter
Has not been spatial, said cannot come back
못온다고?
Cannot come back
그럼 사진은 누가 찍어?
Who does that photograph to illuminate?
아버님, 걱정마세요
The father, your others relieved sits
I all arranged
제가 알아서 할께요
그럼 누굴 불러?
What person are you called?
마을의 사진사가 있으니
Temple mouth that old monkey Yin principle good friend
Pig elder brother kidney
그에게 부탁하면 돼요
That person photographs also has any question
The technology was best
그는 사진을 잘 찍어서
In our entire village he is best
모두 그에게 부탁해요
This person is good
Mr. Xu came
Leads him to go in
거기는 뭐하러 가?
무슨 일을 그렇게 하지?
정말 신경질나는군
Prosperously blesses the business greatly to make money oh!
모두 돈을 벌게 해주세요
Greatly makes money oh! Has oh!
큰 돈을 법시다
All stands, do not have to move heedlessly
All stands, had to illuminate
움직이지 말고 가만히 있어
자, 여러분
Each
Please smile
움직이지 말고 여길 보세요
Must illuminate
됐습니다
Thanks
소화 20년 11월 8일
Shiaowa 20 years in November eighth day
하늘은 맑고 구름이 많았다
Fine day, has the cloud
김광석의원에서 일하려고
The belt father is writing introduction letter
소개장을 들고 그 곳에 갔다
Climbs mountains the gourd stone miner hospital to work
오빠가 시간이 없어서
Elder brother teaches has not been spatial
Is called his good friend article clear to meet me
친구가 대신 마중나왔다
산에는 이미 가을이 와서
On the mountain already had the autumn the cool feeling
경치가 매우 좋았다
The scenery very is along the road good
이런 아름다운 경치를
Thought will be able to suffice in the future to see every day
Such beautiful scenery
자주 보게 돼서 너무 기뻤다
In the heart has one kind of happy feeling
사진이예요
Picture
참 예뻐요
Very attractive
형들이 떠나기 전에 기념으로 찍은거야
아직도 돌아오지 않았어
상해에서 소식이 왔는데
누가 셋째형을 봤대
둘째형은 여송도에 있는데
소식이 없어
여기가 문청의 사진관이야
This is Wen Ch'ing work room
그런데 문청은 어딨지?
The article is clear? The person does not look like in?
아승! 아승!
Arab League victory, Arab League victory
예
문청은 어디 있어?
The article clear goes?
뒤에서 사진 찍어요
Rear photography
가지
Invites
나도 있어
어서 붙여
모두 네 책이야?
These all are your books?
문청의 책도 조금 있어
Major part I, also has Wen Ch'ing
책읽는 걸 좋아하지
All is some bookworms
마르크스를 보네
Looks at Marx?
진보적이군
Very progressive oh
Everybody has the interest, the research has a look
좋아하면 갖다 봐
Mr./Mrs. Lin, the article is clear you to be supposed to know
Also remembers?
임형은 문청을 기억해
The ear hears that
귀가 안들리는 사람이지
문청! 내가 소개하지
Wen Ch'ing
I give you to introduce
임선생님이셔
Mr./Mrs. Lin
반갑습니다
My senior
성함이 이렇게 돼
He should know that, we frequently say
듣지를 못하나봐
만나서 반갑습니다
Chang T'ingk'uan the glory speaks you
이 분은 두선생님이셔
Tangshan comes reporter
Reporter He
Pleases sit down, pleases sit down
앉아, 앉아
Tangshan you quite are ripe
Later very many matters will need to consult to you
지난번 대륙에 가봤더니
도시가 엉망이더군
Tangshan now also in is chaotic
곧 깨끗해지겠지
I looked is person's question
시간이 많이 걸릴거야
The Chen meter comes ??
Not too is same with the Japanese
몇 년으로는 안돼
경비도 많이 들거야
소천 교장선생님이
아프신데도 나가신다고 해서
주사를 놔서 누무시게 하고
정자가 옆에서 간호해요
아버지는 이틀 전부터
Father from two three days ago
진선생님과 같이
On as soon as speaks frankly must go to Tainan
Said Mr. Chen can come to meet him to go together
남대만에 가시겠대요
하지만 진선생님은
But Mr. Chen the quite several years ago died
몇 년전에 돌아가셨어요
아버지도 장례식에 가셨었죠
The father also has attended his funeral
이산가족을 실은 배가
Day before yesterday
Date foreign national sending back place informs
곧 일본에서 돌아오니까
Recently could have the evacuation the ship to Jilong
집에서 기다리시라고 했는데
Is called us not to have to leave home to take a long journey
아버지는 오늘 아침에
Today early morning the father actually reorganizes the baggage to leave in a hurry
짐을 챙기셔서 떠났어요
정말 걱정이 돼요
Let everybody worry
뜨겁다, 뜨겁다, 아주 뜨겁다
다시 한 번
뜨겁다
머리가 아프다
Headache
Headache...
머리가 아프다
배가 아프다
Belly pain
Belly pain...
배가 아프다
어디가 아프십니까?
Your where pain?
움직이지 마십시오
걱정마세요, 괜찮을겁니다
Do not worry
I looked is does not have any relations
돌아온 것만도 다행이니
Can safely come back, is the good fortune
잠시동안 쉬게 하십시오
Temporarily lets him convalesce the period of time in here
어머니에게 문제가 있는 것
Did not know is not
My mother's grave geomancy has the question
같습니다
어머니가 돌아가신 후
Is dead after since her, our four brothers
둘째는 지금까지 소식이 없고
The second child goes to the southern coastal provinces not to have the news
넷째는 귀가 멀고
Old four deafness
셋째는 미쳐서 돌아오다니
Third child or brother the present comes back, sends the insanity
이불을 잘 덮어요
Slightly moves the cotton-wadded quilt
놔요!
The article is good, what do you want to make?
The article is good, do not have like this
문량! 왜 그래? 이러지마
Arab League is good
What are you doing?
이러지마! 그만해
You are going crazy
You are going crazy... ...
Calm 1.
문량, 이게 무슨 짓이야?
문량! 진정해
문량! 문량!
Arab League good, Arab League is good
괜찮아요, 괜찮아요
Not question
광복절을 경축하기 위해
Recovers time
국기를 게양하기로 해서
The celebration recovers
The gauge final conclusion must hang the national flag
모두들 국기를 사느라 바빠
We guarantee the uncle (in long) to be anxious
Is called everybody to buy the national flag to hang
일본 국기는 속이 원이라서
You know the Japanese national flag
Is among the white bottom red
아무렇게나 걸어도 되지만
?? hangs all to, pours is hanging also rightly
Sunny day the flag is dissimilar
우리 국기는 달라
Some people hang quarrel
Sun in above or under
물론이지
많은 사람들이 국기의 태양을
어떻게 게양할지를 몰라
Struggle half of the day
Some people with guarantee are saying in above
태양은 위에 떠있으니
Guarantees is having the knowledge to say very much where has this kind of matter
The sun comes out all over the sky red
The sun should in under
위로 해서 게양하는 집은
Some people do not believe, guarantee the some worries
좀 배운 사람들이야
Or is called everybody to hang according to his meaning
But sends to represent to nine looks
도시인들은 정확히 게양하지
Nine comparisons has the knowledge
Under nine mountains others all hung rightly
하지만 촌사람들은 잘 몰라서
On the mountain has two three is hangs counter-
잘못 게양하는 집이 많아
그래서 서로 자신이 옳다고
Goes back with guarantees was saying
Guarantees the uncle you to be right
많이 싸우지
Guarantees just right is spirited
To the afternoon, has not been right
Some people from nine mountains next time
그리고 어떤 사람은 국기를
잘못 게양하면
Said that, guarantees, you ?? are that absurd
총살이나 투옥될까봐
Under the sun should in above, you hang
You can shoot, is grasped the pass
다시 게양하려다가
Guaranteed the uncle to be anxious
Broadcasts immediately is called everybody to change
5시가 되면 그냥 국기를
Had to change already 5.
Has lowered a flag, without enough time
내려버려
정말 웃기는군
All over the sky red
또 재미있는건
Most interesting was the Japanese national flag useless
일본국기가 필요없어지자
여자들이 일본국기로
Our there women very are all thrifty
애들 옷을 만들었지
Brings makes the clothing to the child, makes the pants
그래서 아이들의 엉덩이는
원숭이처럼 빨개
The child plays in outside
The buttocks all are red
Like monkey
그의 아이들도
The child, Lao Wu also puts on
그런 옷을 입었잖아
자네가 봤어?
You saw right
대륙인들이 알면 창피해
He is reporter
This must write the mainland to go ?? sees the person
이런 일을 기사화하면
절대 안되지
Then my family's national flag
What does your wife want to go makes?
대만 교사들의 엉덩이는
You do not have the child
Said Taiwan teacher buttocks all red
모두 빨갛대, 자 건배
건배
Comes, drinks
Speaks these, loses the dignity
몸 생각해서 조금만 마셔
Cannot drink, but also must drink
웃기지마
Tries to look only then knew
이젠 전쟁도 끝났는데
Now the war all ended
Taiwan now how?
대만은 어떻게 될까?
물론 아주 좋지
Certainly is very good
조국의 품에 다시 안기고
Returns to the motherland the bosom
Sunny day the flag in all directions all sees
사방에서 국기를 볼 수 있잖아
기분이 너무 좋아
Above also has hangs
Under also has hangs
Obtains the motherland to shade the shade
Good, is very warm
솔직히 말해서
The person on one's own side said the sincerity said
진희같은 매국노를
Plants the bandit like Chen Inei also to entrust with heavy responsibility by the motherland
정부가 중용하다니
To national government
I looked also did not have any good wild hope
국민당에게 실망했어
이제 그런 얘기는 그만 하자
Asks, to drink does not discuss the national affairs
자, 건배하고 즐겁게
Comes, to come
Punishes a cup
술이나 마시자
이게 무슨 노래지?
많이 듣던 노랜인데
유망삼부곡이야
정말 그렇군
라디오에서도 자주 들었잖아
우리도 부를 수 있어
Goes into exile the trilogy
그럼 같이 불러보자
좋아
Really, goes into exile the trilogy
Lao Wu, this first song we the radio has listened
Our also meeting
918, 918 그 비참한 때에
We also sing
Good, sings
918, 918 그 비참한 때에
From that pitiful time
내 고향을 떠났었고
많은 보물을 포기했었지
Has been separated from my hometown
유랑, 유랑
Has gotten rid of the inexhaustible buried treasure
많은 날을 갇혀지내면서
Roams about...
유랑, 유랑
All day price in area inside the great wall
언제가 돼야
Roams about...
내 고향으로 돌아갈 수 있나
Which year?
Which month?
Can suffice to return to I that lovable hometown?
언제가 돼야
그 보물들을 찾을 수 있는지
Which year?
Which month?
Can suffice to take back I that inexhaustible buried treasure
아버지! 어머니!
Parents...
Hello, stator young lady
Hello
안녕하세요, 정자씨
Width beautifully in?
The width in is beautifully busy
안녕하세요, 관미씨 계신가요?
In is busy
지금 바쁜대요
Hello, what matter have?
Width beautifully in?
안녕하십니까?
안녕하세요
무슨 일이십니까?
관미씨 계신가요?
She in surgery room
관미씨가..
Looked like finishes
수술실에 있어요
Otherwise you look
아마 수술이 끝났을테니
한 번 가봐
Asks you to wait
그러죠
잠깐 기다리세요
This bamboo sword is elder brother which dies in battle
The most treasure loves thing
이 검은 전사한 제 오빠가
제일 아꼈던 물건이예요
Now already nobody used it
이제 쓸 사람이 없으니까
Asks you to give the wide glory
관영씨에게 주세요
Elder brother also certainly can treasure it
오빠가 소중히 간직할 거예요
This is a poem which my elder brother writes
이건 오빠가 쓴 시인데
He writes this first poem time
Your elder brother also in field
오빠가 이 시를 쓸 때
관영씨도 같이 있었기에
The hope can treat as commemorating together with the bamboo sword
Gives the wide glory
검과 함께 기념으로
관영씨에게 전해주세요
Thanks
고마워요
This is for the width beautiful
이건 관미씨거예요
For me?
제 거요?
Kimono
기모노군요?
Very attractive
정말 예뻐요
But, I cannot accept
하지만 전 받을 수 없어요
This is a thing which the stator most treasure loves
이건 당신이 아끼는 거잖아요
Has not related, asks you to accept
괜찮아요
In the future in remote Japan
전 일본에서 당신이 기모노를
I can think
The width beautifully puts on the kimono attractive appearance
입은 모습을 생각할 거예요
Stator elder sister
정자씨
The long time is indebted your elder brother's attendance
오랫동안 절 돌봐주신 걸
영원히 잊지 않겠어요
After never do not have to forget
멀리 떨어져 있어도
서로 잊지 말기로 해요
I forever remember you
너는 생각하는대로
Although flies upwards goes
멀리 날아가버리고
I soon after come
나도 곧 따라가리
Everybody is same
모두와 함께
The Japanese most appreciates oriental cherry that kind
일본인은 벚꽃이 활짝
Opens to most Man Tsuimei time
피었을 때를 좋아하지
Litchinut is buried together that kind of scene
그 때가 가장 아름다울 때야
They thought the person borns with should be this
그들은 인생도 그렇게 생각해
Meiji time
명치시대때 한 소녀가
Some girl jumps the waterfall suicide...
폭포에서 떨어져 자살했지
Meiji time
명치시대때 한 소녀가
Some girl jumps the waterfall suicide...
폭포에서 떨어져 자살했지
She is not pessimistic, also loses the will
그녀는 실의에 빠져서
Faces the such bright youth
자살한 게 아니라
그녀의 아름다운 청춘이
Fears it once to vanish
Did not know how is good?
사라지는걸 두려워해서
차라리 벚꽃과 같이
Was inferior to on is same with the oriental cherry
At life most beautiful time
인생에서 가장 아름다울 때에
With the wind litchinut
세상을 떠나려고 한 거지
Her posthumous writings
그녀의 유서는 당시 젊은이를
For then young people
Entire all rouses
크게 감동시켰어
At that time was precisely the Meiji Restoration
그 때는 명치유신때문에
Has filled enthusiasm and the spirit time
열기가 가득차 있을 때였어
같은 운명에 처한 벚꽃이여
어서 떠나거라
나도 곧 따라가겠다
모두와 함께
임문량은 몇 호실에 있습니까?
Ask
How many janitors Lin Wenliang is occupied by?
잠깐만요, 찾아볼께요
You wait a bit, I look up
Arab League is good
The business is the person does, to?
아량, 사업은 사람이 하는 거야
사람은 머리만 쓰면
The person, the casual any business all can do
어떤 사업도 할 수 있지
So long as use the brain
Any business all may do
In your family has six ships to?
너희 집엔 6척의 배가 있어
그 배에 쌀과 설탕을 실어
Six ships pack the rice and the sugar
Transports gains the great bill to Shanghai
상해로 가져다 팔고서
올 때 다른 걸 싣고 오면
We make smuggled goods to come in again
Like this runs two, also quickly fishes a lot
Bill Man Man
금방 큰 돈을 벌 수 있어
어때?
How do you look?
형님에게 물어보고요
This matter, I must ask my eldest brother
이런 일도 물어봅니까?
What matter all needs to ask him?
?? any matter all needs to ask him
이런 일을 뭣하러 물어봐?
괜찮으니 우리끼리 하자
The relations, we have not been us
The Shanghai that side we suspend evenly
You felt relieved
상해쪽은 우리가 책임질테니
걱정마
This place relates us very to be also good
이 쪽도 문제없어
The rice sugar does not have the question
머리를 써서 하면 돼
Use the brain we to do
Do not visit the business also promotes
This is not very stupid?
굴러들어온 복을 차지마
건배하자
Comes, bottoms up
임형, 건배합시다
The Arab League good brother, I respects you
Arab League fine, today prepares goods how?
Good
오늘 아가씨들이 괜찮죠?
그래
The Arab League peach, eight tables first go to the turnplate
아도, 다른 자리로 가봐야지
미안해요
Embarrassed
소개하죠, 춘화와 소홍입니다
I introduced
This spring chrysanthemum, this is bright red
These Ashan person from other provinces receives cordially well
Entertains 1.
먼 데서 오신 분들이니 잘 모셔
이게 무슨 짓이야?
What this does?
사업 얘기를 하는데
We discuss the business in here
여자는 왜 불러?
What asks that many women to do?
Has not seen the woman?
Comes, do not manage these Ashan, the seat
신경쓰지 말고 이리 와서 앉아
The red monkey, Ashan was saying any
괜찮아, 괜찮아
Do not manage him
신경쓰지마
임형
같이 사업을 하자고
I asked you to suffice for a long time
Some business wants to ask you to do
자넬 불렀어
You carefully have a look
Looked has any place not to be dissimilar
어디가 다른지 자세히 봐
홍후, 친구를 소개 안해줘?
Red monkey
Your friend does not introduce for me
아가라고 해, 나와 친한 아춘이야
He calls Arab League finely
This is my being intimate, Arab League spring
안녕하세요
Arab League fine gentleman hello
아름답군요
Attractive
별말씀을요, 담배 피우세요
Is you shuts out
Comes, to smoke
제가 붙여드리죠
I help you to light the cigarette
시간있으면 저희집에
Arab League fine gentleman, has spatially wants often to sit
놀러오세요
알겠소
My meeting
고마워요, 홍후
Many thanks
난 이만 들어갈께
The red monkey, I advanced went
이건 가짜 돈인데
This is not false, is real
Only lacks the lid two seals
도장 두 개만 찍으면 진짜야
If covers the seal
Was allowed to take away changes money
큰 돈을 벌겠군
Is gourd Shi Neip'i?
얼마나 갖고 있어?
How many do you have?
한 푸대나 있으니 날 도와줘
A linen bag
You help me to try to find solution
문제없어
Not question
잠깐만요
And so on
한 번만 더 하자
조금 더 잘래요
Others good feel sleepy
Let me rest again a while
하지 말아요
Does not want
어서 와
조금만 더 자고요
And so on, lets me rest again a while
누구야?
Who?
Width beautiful, in is busy?
바쁘세요?
조금요
Is being yes busy
Is this
제가 병원에 있는 동안
This period of time in here
Receives your everybody attendance
모두들 잘 돌봐주셔서
감사의 뜻으로
The belt some fruits give you
과일을 사왔습니다
Thank you everybody
고마워요
Thank you
기륭에서 경찰이 마약밀매자를
That day the Jilong police kill to sell the smoke
Do you have heard?
죽인 걸 알아?
들어서 알아
Has, has heard
You also have hear
Also heard
알고 있었어?
The scene is very excited
Yes, heard the entire street is very spirited
아주 대단했었대
물론 대단했겠지
Certainly excited
그 마약들은 관리들이
Almost leaves the matter
뇌물을 받고 들여보낸 거잖아
Which do these smoke come?
Is not these high officials smuggles
뇌물만 주면 들여올 수 있어
The red package as soon as fills, again many also comes in
The tiger does not hit
Hits some fly mosquito to do
거물은 못잡고 조무라기들이나
잡았겠지
담배 안피워도 괜찮잖아?
This smoke does not repay any relations
안피우면 안돼
The related department, I do not pull out am not good
내가 붙여줄께
지금은 쌀때문에 문제야
The smoke not that is important
The rice only then is important
상해는 쌀이 아주 귀하대
You had not heard Shanghai now Mi T'angtu controls
정부 관리들은 마약만 들여오고
Good price
These high officials continue are the streamer come in
쌀이 부족한걸 상관안해
Mi T'angyeh no matter we do have eat
뇌물만 받고 무조건
All all purse walks
Nearby two gains
대륙으로 보내버려
일제 시대때가
제일 고통스러웠지
Japanese time we most bitter time
The air raid is fiercest, the rice also has the ration
그 땐 쌀값이 52배가 뛰었지만
How long does the Chen meter come? Also a year
The rice rises 52 times
월급은 15%만 올랐어
Our firewood high water how many
Has rises for a minute half wool?
그건 정부 책임이 아니라
Speaks coarse 1.
모두 회사 책임이야
Which this is the government
This is called the company, is right?
진의같은 놈은
Chen meter open company
혼자 회사를 차려서
자신의 이익만 챙기잖아
Most convenient
The money gains toward a pocket attire
여기다 놔요
Also cannot give you Wu
Please eat the steamed rice dumpling
관미씨가 만든 거야
Width beautiful package
맛있겠군
Like this
그런건 문제도 아니야
Actually these all are not the questions
내 생각엔 실업문제가
In my opinion
The true question is is unemployed the question
가장 심각해
맞아
Said good
대륙과 왕래가 있은 후부터
Inland receive ??
많은 대만인들이 직업을 잃었어
Many Taiwan person's original work all did not have
그 중에는 지식층이 많아
Inside these people, some many intellectual
이런 상태가 계속된다면
The intellectual mood evenly could not caress
The work also does not have the outlet
큰 혼란이 일어날 거야
Future I looked sooner or later must make greatly chaotically
지식층만 그런 게 아닐 거야
I look at not only the intellectual
맞아, 군인들도 전쟁이 끝난 뒤
Soldier
Yes, goes by the so the southern coastal provinces to become a soldier
Comes back finds the work
일자리를 못찾아서 난리야
내 친구가 법원에 있는데
An my friend, in court work
새로 부임한 대법원장이
After Ashan chief first receives
The Taiwan person entirely expels
모든 대만인을 내쫓고
자신의 친척들을 취직시켰대
Own wife, brother-in-law
The sister's sons all call
지금 법원은 그들의 집이 됐어
Now the entire court turns their family to open
모두 친척들이야?
Own open
To, own open the court
맞아
This makes sense
그건 잘한 일이야
너같은 일본놈 앞잡이는
Like your this kind of person
당연히 바꿔야지
Japanese government's enslavement
Must trade
웃기고 있네
Also cannot say the Tangshan speech
Enslavement, his mother's enslavement
우리의 팔자는 노예야
운명이 그렇게 만들었어
The enslavement is we wants
We that are inexpensive?
청나라도 우리의 의견을
Initially also was the Qing Dynasty sells out us
무시해버리고
마관조약을 맺었잖아
Treaty of Shimonoseki some who have asked
Does our Taiwan person want?
그런 말은 그만해
Comes, to drink, drinks
After all a speech
국민당의 법이 바뀌지 않는 한
National government's procedure if is also invariable
우린 계속 고통받으며 살 거야
The Sino-Japanese War although wins
그럼 언제 편하게 살 수 있지?
The common people also want the pain to be very long
기다려야지
Such speech
We must wait till any time only then had the day before
Does not know
기다려봤자 소용없어
And so on
And so on is useless
국민들이 들고 일어나서
If wants to have the future
According to mine view
뒤엎어야 돼
Suffers hardships common people
Own bravely want to stand up
국민당이 계속 진의에게
The national government lets Chen I do like this again
정치를 맡긴다면
대만은 언젠간 큰일날 거야
I looked that, Taiwan sooner or later must have an accident
Lao He
그 때가 되면 막기에는
Taiwan certainly can have an accident
너무 늦어져
Prepares your pen
When the time comes you are the testimony
그만하고 술이나 마시자
Respects the testimony, the respect testimony,
천천히 마셔
독일에서 전해오는 명곡으로
오래된 전설이 담겨있어요
아름다운 귀신이 라인강에
살고 있었는데
자주 강변에서 노래를 불렀어요
지나가는 어부들이 그 노래
소리에 심취해서 배가 암초에
부딪치는 바람에 많은 사람이
죽었대요
난 8살까진 말을 했던
기억이 있었는데
그 땐 크게 노래를 부르며
거리를 다녔어
그래서 사람들이
내가 배우가 되길 바랬지
난 8살 때 나무에서 떨어져
머리를 다쳐서 집에 누워
있으면서 제대로 걷지도 못했어
귀가 안들리는지 몰랐는데
아버지가 글로 가르쳐 주셨어
그 땐 어려서 슬픈 것도 모르고
그냥 즐겁게 놀았어
울지마
착하지
이 것 보렴
울지 마라, 착하지
???
아빠가 안아줄께
Has a fever
먼저 내려가 있어
The father hurts, the father hurts
우리 애기 착하지, 울지마
You first arrive building inferior me
약 갖고 올께
착하지
And so on takes the medicine to eat to him
How?
In here
어때?
여기 있어
Eldest brother
형님
Brings
내놔, 어서!
Brings!
그건..
What is this?
이게 뭐야? 뭐야?
This is any
Does your mother
빌어먹을!
Is called you eldest brother
가서 네 두목을 불러와!
Does your mother, what smoke pulls out?
어디서 담배를 피워?
Steps on extinguishes
어서 꺼!
Your eye was blind
That writes any you not to see
눈이 멀었어?
저기 써 있는게 안보여?
Dry!
망할 자식
죽고 싶어서 환장했군
You really die young
This kind of matter you also do obtain
감히 이런 짓을 해?
What does?
왜 그래?
Is called you eldest brother to come
Does your mother, you go or do not go?
가서 두목을 불러오라니까
뭐해?
Is called you eldest brother
두목님을 모셔와
My money does not suffice you to spend is not?
내가 준 돈이 부족해?
You knew the matter accidentally explodes
이 일이 들통나면
How many people can kill you to know?
수많은 사람들이 죽게 돼
Also must tow including me dies
나까지도 죽게 돼
Has the matter I to take on
제가 책임질께요
Takes on your mother
빌어먹을, 네가 뭘 책임져?
What do you have to take on?
The cargo owner writes is Lin Wenhsiung, I
물건의 주인은
임문웅으로 되어 있어
Also was saying the boast, does your mother
그래도 큰소리야? 망할 녀석
Puts on this appearance with these Shanghai men
옷은 대륙사람처럼 입고서
Is popular with others
유행을 따라가는군
Is not a thing
못된 자식
Arab League common people?
아량은 어디 있어?
Did not know
몰라요
You meet did not know?
하루종일 같이 있었는데
Your two all day trousers joint in belting in same place
You meet did not know?
왜 몰라?
You said
말해요
Really does not know
정말 몰라요
빌어먹을
The Wenzhou man, makes the phone call to Mr. Xu
온노야, 허선생에게 전화해
Feeds, helps me to meet 24
여보세요, 24번 좀 부탁해요